Finding Aid for C. Loring Brace papers, 1954-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Correspondence, 1966-2002
  - Stevens and Smart, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Stewart, Alicia, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Stocking, George, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Stocking, George (Chicago), 1994-1996 (Box 7)
  - Stoker, Teresa, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Strassmann, Beverly, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Stringer and Gamble, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Suchey, Judy, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Susser, Ida, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Sutter, Rick, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Suzuki, Takao, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Swindler, Daris, 1992-1998 (Box 7)
  - Szalay, Fred, 1989-1995 (Box 7)
  - Szathmary, Emoke, 1998 (Box 7)
  - T, 1967-1972 (Box 7)
  - T, 1974-1982 (Box 7)
  - T, 1984-1990 (Box 7)
  - Takezawa, Yasuko, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Takezawa, Yasuko (Fullbright), 2004 (Box 8)
  - Tattersall, Ian, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Texas Skull, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Tracer, David, 1990-1998 (Box 8)
  - Travel, University of Michigan, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Trinkaus, Eric, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
  - Tumen, Dashtseveg, 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Turner, Christy G. II, 1977-1996 (Box 8)
  - Turp, Jens, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Tyler, Donald, 1992-1998 (Box 8)
  - Tyler, Donald, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Tyler, Donald, 2005 (Box 8)
  - U, 1984-1995 (Box 8)
  - V, 1968-1978 (Box 8)
  - V, 1984-1990 (Box 8)
  - Valparaiso University, 1968 (Box 8)
  - von Hippel, 1995 (Box 8)
  - W, 1967-1981 (Box 8)
  - W, 1973-1987 (Box 8)
  - W, 1984-1995 (Box 8)
  - Walker, Alan, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Walters, Richard, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Ward, Ryk, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Ward, Steve, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Washburn festschrift, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Washburn, Sherwood, 1958-1977 (Box 8)
  - Watanabe, Hitoshi, 1984-1987 (Box 8)
  - Wei, Boyuan, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Weiss, Kenneth, 1971-1976 (Box 8)
  - Weiss, Kenneth, 1991-2002 (Box 8)
  - Weiss, Mitch, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
  - Westergaard, 1991-1995 (Box 8)
  - WETA Washington D.C, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - White, Tim, 1974-2003 (Box 8)
  - White, Tim, 1986 (Box 39)
    [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2016 ]
  - Wilkinson, Richard, 1968-1972 (Box 8)
  - Willermet, Cathy, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Williams College, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Katherine, 1985-1996 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Robert C., 1971-1980 (Box 8)
  - Wine, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Wolfe, Andrew, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Wood, Henry, 2005 (Box 8)
  - Wrangham, Richard, 1985-2003 (Box 8)
  - Wolpoff, Milford, 1966-1980 (Box 8)
  - Wu, Mengxin, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Wu, Rukang, 1980-1985 (Box 8)
  - Wu, Xinzhi, 1981-1990 (Box 8)
  - X, Y, Z, 1984-1991 (Box 8)
  - X, Y, Z, 1974-1990 (Box 8)
  - Yaroch, Lucia, 1982-2004 (Box 8)
  - Yellen-Paleoanthropology Society, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Zhang, Huaitao, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Tracer, David, 1990-1998 (Box 8)
  - Travel, University of Michigan, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Trinkaus, Eric, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
  - Tumen, Dashtseveg, 1997-1998 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1986-2009
  The Correspondence, 1986-2009 (4.25 linear feet) series holds a separate correspondence file created by Brace with content from the late 1980s to 2009. Materials here relate to Brace's research work, his career at the University of Michigan, including, communication with colleagues in the field of anthropology, professional organizations, publishers, and students. A large amount of material received unfiled was categorized as Miscellaneous and arranged by year from 1973 to 2009. Most of the correspondents found in the previous series are also present in this one including extensive correspondence with Dean Falk, Noriko Segughi, and Russell Nelson. Some additional correspondents include: Serpil Eroglu, S.O.Y. Keita, and Richard Wrangham.
  - Abdi, Kamyar Report, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Allegreto, Kimberly, 2004 (Box 8)
  - American Indian Intertribal Association, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Aoki, Kenichi, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Asheshov, Natalia, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Brown, Angela, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Clark, Geoffrey A., 2000 (Box 8)
  - Colonna, Camille, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Cook, Della (Franchthi), 1998 (Box 8)
  - Cranbrook Institute of Science, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Cudel, Evelyne, 2006 (Box 8)
  - Gurtis, Greg, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Dagosto, Marian, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Dawes, Donald, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Delisle, Richard, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Dennell, Robin, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Douglas, Bernie, 2008 (Box 8)
  - Ellzey, Thomas S., 1997 (Box 9)
  - Eroglu, Serpil, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Eroglu, Serpil, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Fairbridge, Rhodes, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Falk, Dean, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Falk, Dean, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Falk, Dean, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Falk, Dean, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Finney, Ben, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Fitzhugh, William -- Kennewick, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Fortin, Richard, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Franchino, Nick, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Frey, Brent, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Frey, Brent, 2005 (Box 9)
  - Friedlander, Jonathan, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Garn, Barbara, 2004-2006 (Box 9)
  - Garn, Stanley, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Gorman, Rachael, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Graver, Anne L., 1992 (Box 9)
  - Graves, Joe, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Guidon, Ni칟de, 2001-2003 (Box 9)
  - Hanihara, Kazuro, 2005 (Box 9)
  - Hartley, Andrew, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Haviland, William, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Heathcote, Gary, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Hinton, Robert, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Hisamitsu, Mitsihiro, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Inamori Foundation, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Jones, Chad, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Jurmain, Robert, 2006-2007 (Box 9)
  - Kaufman, Matthew, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Keita, S.O.Y., 2007 (Box 9)
  - Keita, S.O.Y., 2008 (Box 9)
  - Kittinger, Paul M., 2004 (Box 9)
  - Kluwer, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Krantz, Grover, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Kubota, Kinziro, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Lasker, Gabriel, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Leaky Foundation, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Leaky Foundation, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Licurgo do Amaral, Heleno, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Lieberman and Reynolds (Montagu Festschrift), 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - McDaniel, Michael, 2002 (Box 9)
  - McGill, Chaundra, 2006 (Box 9)
  - McIntosh and Otis, 2006 (Box 9)
  - McKee, Jeff, 2001 (Box 9)
  - McKie, Jeff, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Media Education Foundation, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Michigan Archaeological Society, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-1979 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980-1989 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-1994 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995-1999 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000-2001 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 2004; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2005; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2006; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2007; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2008; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2008; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 2008-2009 (Box 11)
  - Molnar, Stephen, 1999 (Box 11)
  - Montagu Institute, 2000-2002 (Box 11)
  - Moses, Yolanda, 2008 (Box 11)
  - Nawrocki, Stephen, 1992 (Box 11)
  - Naylor, Paz, 2008 (Box 11)
  - Neel, James, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 2001 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 2001-2003 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 2003-2005 (Box 11)
  - Nelson, Russell, 2006-2008 (Box 11)
  - Neuratt, Elizabeth, 2006 (Box 11)
  - The New York Times, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Office of the Vice-President for Research, 2005 (Box 11)
  - Osher Lifelong Learning Institute, 2007 (Box 11)
  - Oubre, Alondra, 2005 (Box 11)
  - Peregrine, Peter, 2000-2002 (Box 11)
  - Petrusewsky, Mike, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Presswood, Ron, 2004 (Box 11)
  - Pretell, Jaime, 2007 (Box 11)
  - Quinty, Conrad, 2005-2007 (Box 11)
  - Race -- Affirmative Action, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Reed, Edward, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Relethford, John, 1997-2002 (Box 11)
  - Rice, Patricia, 1997-1999 (Box 11)
  - Sanchez Hall, Alison, 2006 (Box 11)
  - Scott, Eugenie C., 1976 (Box 11)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 2004; 1 folders (Box 11)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 2004; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 2005 (Box 12)
  - Seguchi, Noriko,2005 --, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 2006; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 2007-2008 (Box 12)
  - Shanghai Antique Store, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Shettler, Jaclyn, 2007 (Box 12)
  - Smith, Fred, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Smith, Patricia, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Southern Methodist University, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Spencer, Frank, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Spencer, Frank, 1992-1993 (Box 12)
  - Spencer, Frank, 2000-2004 (Box 12)
  - Stewart, Elizabeth, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Stoker, Teresa, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Susser, Ida, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Szathm치ry, Emoke J.E. (Box 12)
  - Takezawa, Yasuko, 2007 (Box 12)
  - Tattersall, Ian, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Tracer, David, 2007 (Box 12)
  - Toronto Opera, 2006 (Box 12)
  - UC Press, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Urban, Greg, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Wall of Tolerance, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Washington, Marc, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Weide, Denise, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Wllermet, Catherine, 2005 (Box 12)
  - Wood, Henry, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Wrangham, Richard, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Wrangham, Richard, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Yahya, Harun, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Yelvingto, Kevin-Coon, 2004 (Box 12)
- Professional Service and Activities
  The Professional Service and Activities series, 1964-2006 (3.75 linear feet), is comprised of two subseries, Societies and Organizations and Conferences and Presentations. This series is made up of materials that document Brace's involvement with anthropological and other professional organizations, as well as in symposia, lectures, conferences and other forums. Materials include correspondence, paperwork related to the planning and participation in events, and records of his work as officer in some of these organizations. Contents are arranged alphabetically.
  - Societies and Organizations
    - American Anthropological Association
      - Nominations, 1970 (Box 12)
      - Bulletin, 1971 (Box 12)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 12)
      - Toronto, 1972 (Box 12)
      - 1987 (Box 12)
      - 1988 (Box 12)
      - 1988 (Box 12)
      - 1989 (Box 12)
      - 1991 (Box 13)
      - 1992 (Box 13)
      - 1994 (Box 13)
      - 1995 (Box 13)
      - 1996 (Box 13)
      - 1997 (Box 13)
      - 1998 (Box 13)
      - 1999, 4 folders (Box 13)
      - Anthropology Newsletter, 1999 (Box 13)
      - 2000 (Box 13)
      - Symposium, 2000 (Box 13)
      - 2001 (Box 13)
      - 2006 (Box 13)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science
      - 1995 (Box 13)
      - 1995 (Box 13)
      - 1996 (Box 13)
      - Section H Chair, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - 1998 (Box 13)
      - Smithsonian, 1998 (Box 13)
      - 1999 (Box 13)
      - Anaheim Symposium, 5 folders (Box 13)
      - 2003 (Box 13)
    - American Association of Physical Anthropologists
      - 1964-1971 (Box 13)
      - Nominations, 1971-1972 (Box 14)
      - 1972 (Box 14)
      - Problems in Early Hominid Interpretations,1972 (Box 14)
      - Dallas, 1973 (Box 14)
      - 1975 (Box 14)
      - 1976 (Box 14)
      - 1977 (Box 14)
    - American Association of Physical Anthropologists
      - Nominations, 1977-1978 (Box 14)
      - 1978 (Box 14)
      - 1979 (Box 14)
      - 1980 (Box 14)
      - 1980 (Box 14)
      - 1981 (Box 14)
      - 1982 (Box 14)
      - 1983 (Box 14)
      - 1984 (Box 14)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 14)
      - 1987, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Kansas City, 1988 (Box 14)
      - 1989 (Box 14)
      - 1991 (Box 14)
      - 1992 (Box 14)
      - 1993 (Box 14)
      - 1994, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Oak, 1995 (Box 14)
      - Durham, 1996 (Box 14)
      - 1997 (Box 14)
      - 1998 (Box 14)
      - 1999 (Box 14)
      - 2000, 3 folders (Box 14)
      - 2001 (Box 15)
      - 2002 (Box 15)
      - 2003 (Box 15)
      - 2004 (Box 15)
      - 2005 (Box 15)
      - 2006 (Box 15)
    - Canadian Association of Physical Anthropology, 1982-1994 (Box 15)
    - Dental Anthropology Association
      - 1989 (Box 15)
      - 1990 (Box 15)
      - 1987-1997 (Box 15)
    - Indo-Pacific Prehistory Association, 1990-1992 (Box 15)
    - International Association of Human Biologists, 1968 (Box 15)
    - Paleoanthropology Society, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Society of American Archaeology, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research
      - 1977 (Box 15)
      - 1973-1979 (Box 15)
      - 1985 (Box 15)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Conferences and Presentations
    - American Academy of Forensic Sciences Meeting, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Circum-Pacific Prehistory Conference, 1989; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Indiana University David Skomp Lecture in Anthropology, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Indo-Pacific Prehistory Association -- Yogyakarta, 1990; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - International Symposium: The Fossil Man of Monte Circeo, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Inter-Congress of the International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences
      - 2002-2004, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - 2003 (Box 16)
    - Micronesian Archaeological Conference, 1987 (Box 16)
    - Idwest Conference on Asian Affairs, 1982 (Box 16)
    - NAGPRA Meeting -- Cambridge, 1997 (Box 16)
    - Pacific Science Congress, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Prehistoric Mongoloid Dispersals International Conference, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Takezawa, Watanabe, and Brace, undated (Box 16)
    - Ninth International Symposium on Dental Morphology, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Symposium on the Development of Human Intelligence, undated (Box 16)
    - Symposium on Japanese Archaeology and Prehistory, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Symposium: Sexual Dimorphism, 1988 (Box 16)
    - University of California, Santa Barbara, Spring Speakers Series, 1998 (Box 16)
    - University of Chicago: Anthropology, Postwar/ Premillenial:Intergenerational Conversations, 1996 (Box 16)
    - University of Minnesota Undergraduate Anthropology Conference, 2001 (Box 16)
    - University of Tokyo Symposium, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Vancouver, 1983 (Box 16)
- Publications
  The Publications series, 1963-2007 (6.5 linear feet) is the most extensive series in the collection. Materials are arranged in six groupings; publishers, journals, articles, book reviews, encyclopedias, and books. These are organized alphabetically with the exception of the articles which are arranged by year. Contents include correspondence regarding his books and articles and documentation of his work as a reviewer for academic journals.
  - Altamira Press
    - 1996 (Box 16)
    - 1998-2000, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - 2006 (Box 16)
  - Cambridge University Press, 2000 (Box 16)
  - CRM Books, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Harper and Row, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Harvard University Press
    - 1992-1998 (Box 16)
    - 2004 (Box 16)
    - 2008 (Box 16)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston
    - Brief Atlas of Human Evolution, 1963-1974 (Box 16)
    - Atlas -- Permissions, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
    - Atlas of Human Evolution, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Atlas of Human Evolution, 1979-1986 (Box 16)
  - Macmillan Publishing, 1968-1982 (Box 16)
  - McGraw-Hill
    - 1971-1996 (Box 16)
    - 1998 (Box 16)
    - 2002 (Box 16)
  - New York Times (Box 17)
    - 1989-2003 (Box 17)
  - Book Review, 1998-2004
    - 2005 (Box 17)
  - Palgrave Macmillan, 2006 (Box 17)
  - Paradigm Publishers, 2004 (Box 17)
  - University of Arizona Press, 2004 (Box 17)
  - University of Michigan Press, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Wiley
    - 1972 (Box 17)
    - 1972-1998 (Box 17)
  - Yale University Press, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Advances in Dental Anthropology, 1989 (Box 17)
  - Allyn and Bacon, 2003 (Box 17)
  - American Anthropologist
    - 1977 (Box 17)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 17)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 17)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 17)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 17)
    - 1994 (Box 17)
    - 1995 (Box 17)
    - 1996 (Box 17)
    - 1997 (Box 17)
    - 1998 (Box 17)
    - 1999 (Box 17)
    - 2001 (Box 17)
    - 2006 (Box 17)
    - 2008 (Box 17)
  - American Antiquity, 2001 (Box 17)
  - American Journal of Human Biology
    - 1998 (Box 17)
    - 2005 (Box 17)
  - American Journal of Human Genetics
    - 1972 (Box 17)
  - American Journal of Physical Anthropology
    - 1964-1972 (Box 17)
    - 1974-1979 (Box 17)
    - 1980-1987 (Box 17)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 17)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 17)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 17)
    - 2002-2004 (Box 17)
  - American Naturalist, 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - American Psychologist, 1995 (Box 17)
  - American Scientist, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Annals of Human Biology
    - 1975-1994 (Box 17)
    - 1986 (Box 17)
    - 1987 (Box 17)
  - Anthropological Science, 2006 (Box 17)
  - Asian Perspectives
    - 1984 (Box 17)
    - 1998 (Box 17)
  - Athena Review
    - 2001 (Box 17)
    - 2002 (Box 17)
  - Behavioral and Brain Sciences
    - 1980 (Box 17)
    - 1988 (Box 17)
    - 1989 (Box 17)
    - 1992 (Box 17)
    - 1993 (Box 17)
    - 1994 (Box 17)
    - 1995 (Box 17)
    - 1996 (Box 17)
    - 1997 (Box 17)
    - 2002 (Box 18)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 18)
  - Book World, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Comparative Studies in Society and History, 2003 (Box 18)
  - Connective Tissue, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Creation/ Evolution, 1986; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Current Anthropology
    - 1967-1969 (Box 18)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 18)
    - 1978 (Box 18)
    - 1979 (Box 18)
    - 1979 (Box 18)
    - 1981 (Box 18)
    - 1982 (Box 18)
    - 1983 (Box 18)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 18)
    - 1988 (Box 18)
    - 1990 (Box 18)
    - 1991 (Box 18)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 18)
    - 1995 (Box 18)
    - 2001 (Box 18)
    - 2002 (Box 18)
    - 2008 (Box 18)
  - Dental Anthropology, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Evolution, 1987 (Box 18)
  - General Anthropology, 1999-2002 (Box 18)
  - Human Biology
    - 2000 (Box 18)
    - 2001 (Box 18)
    - 2003 (Box 18)
  - Human Ecology, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Human Evolution
    - 1985 (Box 18)
    - 1988-1998 (Box 18)
    - 1993 (Box 18)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 18)
  - Human Nature Review, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Journal of Anatomy, 2004 (Box 18)
  - Journal of Anthropological Research
    - 1998 (Box 18)
    - 1999, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - 2001 (Box 18)
  - Journal of Comparative Human Biology HOMO, 2003-2006 (Box 18)
  - Journal of Forensic Sciences
    - 1994 (Box 18)
    - 1995 (Box 18)
  - Journal of the History of Behavioral Sciences, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Journal of Human Evolution, 1999 (Box 18)
  - Journal of the Royal Anthropological Institute, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Man
    - 1977 (Box 18)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 18)
  - Micronesica, 1990 (Box 18)
  - National Geographic Society, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Natural History
    - 1969-1972 (Box 18)
    - 1975 (Box 18)
    - 1994 (Box 18)
    - 1996 (Box 18)
    - 1997 (Box 18)
    - 2003 (Box 18)
    - 2007 (Box 18)
  - Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council Canada, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Nature (Box 19)
    - 1989 (Box 19)
    - 2000 (Box 19)
    - 2004 (Box 19)
    - 2005 (Box 19)
    - 2006 (Box 19)
  - Patterns of Prejudice, 2004 (Box 19)
  - Perspectives in Human Biology, 1998-2000 (Box 19)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences
    - 1991, 1998 (Box 19)
    - 2000 (Box 19)
    - 2001 (Box 19)
    - 2003 (Box 19)
    - 2004 (Box 19)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 19)
  - Psycoloquy
    - 1999, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - 2000 (Box 19)
  - Quarterly Review of Biology, 2001; 2 folders
    - Reviews in anthropology (Box 19)
    - 1985 (Box 19)
    - 1996 (Box 19)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 19)
  - Sarawak Museum Journal, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Science
    - 1968-1969 (Box 19)
    - 1974 (Box 19)
    - 1975 (Box 19)
    - 1983 (Box 19)
    - 1989 (Box 19)
    - 1994 (Box 19)
    - 1996 (Box 19)
    - 1998 (Box 19)
    - 1999 (Box 19)
    - 2001 (Box 19)
    - 2002 (Box 19)
    - 2003 (Box 19)
    - 2004 (Box 19)
    - 2005 (Box 19)
  - Science Online, 1999 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American, 1970-1997 (Box 19)
  - Social Science Information sur les Sciences Sociales, 1999 (Box 19)
  - "On the Race Concept,", 1964 (Box 19)
  - "The Fate of the Classic Neanderthal,", 1964 (Box 19)
  - "Dietary Hypothesis and Early Hominid Interpretations,", 1965 (Box 19)
  - "Experimental Studies in Human Tooth Wear,", 1967 (Box 19)
  - "Ridiculed, Rejected but Still Our Ancestor,", 1968 (Box 19)
  - "Reply: On the Dating of the Krapina Man Finds,", 1969 (Box 19)
  - " Comment on A Survey of the Evidence for Intrahuman Killing in the Pleistocene. M. K. Roper.", 1969 (Box 19)
  - "Fossil Hominid Taxonomy,", 1969 (Box 19)
  - "Bone Strontium and Diet", 1971 (Box 19)
  - "Homo sapiens," Chapter 12. In Anthropology Today. CRM Books, 1971 (Box 19)
  - "On Creeping Jensenism,", 1971 (Box 19)
  - "Race and Intelligence,", 1971 (Box 19)
  - "Post-Pleistocene in the Human Dentition,", 1971 (Box 19)
  - "Homo habilis" Tested by Tooth Measurements,", 1971 (Box 19)
  - "Tooth Measurements and the Rejection of the Taxon "Homo habilis.",", 1971 (Box 19)
  - "Foreword". In Introduction to Fossil Man. Frank E. Poirier, 1972 (Box 19)
  - "Sexual Dimorphism in Human Evolution,", 1972 (Box 19)
  - "Tooth Feature Recording Form,", 1972 (Box 19)
  - "Back to the Bow and Arrow". Review of The Tender Carnivore and the Sacred Game. Paul Shepard. Natural History 82(9):110--117, 1973 (Box 19)
  - "Intellectual History and the Race Concept,", 1972 (Box 19)
  - "Refocusing on the Neanderthal Problem,", 1973 (Box 19)
  - "Sexual Dimorphims and the Australopithecine Range of Variation,", 1973 (Box 20)
  - "The Isolation of Temperament Dimensions in Dogs,", 1973 (Box 20)
  - "The Measures of Man,", 1974 (Box 20)
  - "Technology versus Tooth Size in Australasia,", 1975 (Box 20)
  - "Tooth Reduction in the Orient,", 1976 (Box 20)
  - "A Sermon on the Flat,", 1976 (Box 20)
  - "Monkey Business and Bird Brains,", 1976 (Box 20)
  - "Tooth Size and Austronesian Origins,", 1976 (Box 20)
  - "Biological Parameters and Pleistocene Hominid Life-Ways,", 1977-1979 (Box 20)
  - "Occlusion to the Anthropological Eye". In The Biology of Occlusal Development. J. A. McNamara, Jr., ed. Pp. 179--209. Monograph No. 7, Craniofacial Growth Series. Ann Arbor: Center for Human Growth and Development, The University of Michigan, 1977 (Box 20)
  - Anthropology 701, 1977 (Box 20)
  - "Pleistocene Hominid Tooth Size and Life-Way,", 1977 (Box 20)
  - "Krapina, "Classic" Neanderthals, and the Evolution of the European Face,", 1979 (Box 20)
  - "Tooth Size and Austronesian Origins,", 1980 (Box 20)
  - "Sexual Dimorphism and Human Tooth Size Differences,", 1980 (Box 20)
  - "Australian Tooth Size Clines and the Death of a Stereotype,", 1980 (Box 20)
  - "Tales of the Phylogenetic Woods: The Evolution and Significance of Phylogenetic Trees,"1981 (Box 20)
  - "The Total Morphological Neanderthal as Rumpelstilzchen,", 1981 (Box 20)
  - "Debate wit Duane Gish: Creation vs Evolution,", 1982 (Box 20)
  - "Vancouver Presentation,", 1983 (Box 20)
  - "Research on Human Post--Pleistocene Dentofacial Size Changes in Asia: Status and Prospects,", 1983 (Box 20)
  - "Prehistoric and Modern Tooth Size in China,", 1984 (Box 20)
  - "Egg on the Face, F in the Mouth, and the Overbite,", 1986 (Box 20)
  - "Gradual Change in Human Tooth Size in the Late Pleistocene and Post-Pleistocene,", 1987 (Box 20)
  - "Craniofacial Comparison of Circum-Pacific Peoples,", 1989 (Box 20)
  - "Australia in Craniodental Perspective,", 1988 (Box 20)
  - "Punctuation, Cladistics and the Legacy of Medieval Platonism,", 1988 (Box 20)
  - "A Theory of Human and Primate Evolution,", 1989 (Box 20)
  - "Reflections on the Face of Japan: A Multivariate Craniofacial and Odontometric Perspective,", 1989 (Box 20)
  - "A Non-Racial Craniofacial Perspective on Human Variation: A(ustralia) to Z(uni),", 1990 (Box 20)
  - "The Creation of Specific Hominid Names: Gloria in excelsis Deo? Or Ego? Or Praxis?,", 1990 (Box 20)
  - "Micronesians, Asians, Thais and Relations: A Craniofacial and Odontometric Perspective,", 1990 (Box 20)
  - "What Big Teeth You Had Grandma! Human Tooth Size, Past and Present,", 1991 (Box 20)
  - "Monte Circeo, Neanderthals, and Continuity in European Cranial Morphology,", 1991 (Box 20)
  - "Dimensions of Face in Asia in the Perspective of Geography and Prehistory,", 1991 (Box 20)
  - "Adaptive and Non-Adaptive Aspects of Human Biological Variation,", 1991 (Box 20)